Guide to the Roundtable for Women in Foodservice Archive 1983-2001 MSS.229
Fales Library and Special Collections
Roundtable for Women in Foodservice Archive
1983-2001
Fales Library and Special Collections
Roundtable of Women in Foodservice, Inc.
MSS.229
3.75 Linear Feet (3 boxes)
The Roundtable for Women in Foodservice, Inc., is an organization devoted to the advancement of women in all segments of the foodservice industry. This collection contains materials related to the Roundtable's operations between 1983 and 2001.
Arrangement
Materials in the collection are arranged entirely as they were received, with the exception of all multimedia items, which were removed to Series IV. All efforts were made to preserve the original arrangement of the materials; the series in the collection and their titles reflect RWF's own arrangement strategy.
Missing Title
Series I: Roundtable Meetings and Events
Series II: Board Meeting Minutes
Series III: Organization Records
Series IV: Media
Conditions Governing Access
Materials are open to researchers. Please contact the Fales Library and Special Collections, fales.library@nyu.edu, 212-998-2596.
Provenance
This collection was donated to the Fales Library by Roundtable for Women in Foodservice, Inc. in 2008.
Scope and Content
The materials in the collection relate to the administration and operation of the Roundtable for Women in Foodservice between 1983 and 2001. The collection contains documentation of the Roundtable's public events and board meetings, as well as publications by and about the Roundtable.
Biographical / Historical
The Roundtable for Women in Foodservice, Inc. (RWF) was founded in 1983 in New York City. From its inception, its mission has been to aid the career advancement of women within all creative, administrative, and entrepreneurial segments of the foodservice industry.
Food industry and trade -- United States.; Women cooks -- United States.; Food industry and trade -- United States -- Societies, etc.; Women cooks |z United States |x History |y 20th century.; Women |z United States |x Societies and Clubs.; Records (documents); Cooks -- United States; Cooks -- United States -- History -- 20th century; Roundtable of Women in Foodservice, Inc.
- Series I: Roundtable Meetings and Events, 1983-2001
  Arrangement Note
  Materials are arranged chronologically, as received from RWF. Each folder listed contains a number of folders labeled by RWF administrators.
  Scope and Content
  This series contains materials related to public and member events orchestrated by the Roundtable for Women in Foodservice. Regular meetings and panel discussions are addressed in this series, as well as special events and award ceremonies. Yearly calendars are interspersed throughout the series.
  - Meetings, 1983-1985 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Meetings, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    General
    Note: Audiocassette in folder labeled "Nov. 1, 1986" removed to Series IV: Media.
  - Calendar and Meetings, 1986-1987 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Meetings and Workshops, Jan-Mar 1988 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Meetings, Apr-Jun 1988 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Meetings, Jul-Dec 1988 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Calendar and Meetings, Jan-Apr 1991 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Meetings and Events, May-Dec 1991 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Calendar and Meetings, Jan-Mar 1992 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    Note: Audiocassette in folder labeled "Feb 3 1992" removed to Series IV: Media.
  - Meetings, Apr-Jun 1992 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Meetings, Jul-Dec 1992 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Calendar and Meetings, Jan-Mar 1993 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    Note: Audiocassettes from 1 February and 1 March meetings removed to Series IV: Media.
  - Meetings, Apr-Jun 1993 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Meetings, Jul-Dec 1993 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Calendar, Meetings and Events, Jan-Jun 1994 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Meetings and Events, Aug-Dec 1994 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Calendar and Meetings, Jan-Feb 1995 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Meetings, Mar-Jun 1995 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Meetings, Jul-Sep 1995 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Woman of Distinction Award Ceremony, 2 Oct 1995 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Woman of Distinction Award Ceremony, 2 Oct 1995 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Calendar and Meetings, Oct 1995-Jan 1996 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Meetings, Feb-Apr 1996 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Meetings, May-Aug 1996 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Meetings and Events, Sep-Dec 1996 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Calendar and Meetings, Jan-Mar 1997 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Meetings, Apr-Jun 1997 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Meetings, Jul-Sep 1997 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Meetings, Oct-Dec 1997 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Calendar and Meetings, Jan-Mar 1998 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Meetings, May-Aug 1998 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Woman of Distinction Award Ceremony, 5 Oct 1998 (Box 2, Folder 13, Folder 14)
  - Meetings, Nov 1998-Apr 1999 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Meetings, Jun-Dec 1999 (Box 2, Folder 16)
    Includes materials related to the Woman of Distinction Ceremony of 1999.
  - Woman of Distinction Award Ceremony, 6 Nov 2000 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Event Notices, 2000-2001 (Box 2, Folder 18)
- Series II: Board Meeting Minutes
  This series contains minutes from the Roundtable's board meetings.
  - Board Meeting Minutes, 1984-1991 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Board Meeting Minutes, 1987 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Board Meeting Minutes, 1988 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Board Meeting Minutes, 1989 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Board Meeting Minutes, 1990 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Board Meeting Minutes, 1995 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Board Meeting Minutes, 1997 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Board Meeting Minutes, 1998-1999 (Box 3, Folder 4)
- Series III: Organization Records
  This series contains records amassed by the Roundtable. Types of materials include a chapter handbook, local and national newsletters, member directories, and press related to members of the RWF.
  Materials are arranged alphabetically by subject, as received from RWF. Each folder listed contains a number of folders labeled by RWF administrators.
  - Chapter Handbook, November 1993 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Chapter Handbook, November 1993 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Chapter Handbook, November 1993 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Chapter Handbook, November 1993 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Chapter Handbook, November 1993 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Chapter Handbook, November 1993 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Chapter Handbook, November 1993 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Chapter Handbook, November 1993 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Directories, 1983-1995 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Directories, 1995-1999 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Metro Chapter Newsletters, 1986-1994 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Metro Chapter Newsletters, 1995-2001 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - National Newsletters, 1990-1998 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Organizational Notes, 1983-1987 (Box 3, Folder 18)
    Note: Contents include historical notes, factsheets, chapter guidelines and by-laws.
  - Press Coverage of Members, 1990-1991 (Box 3, Folder 19)
- Series IV: Media
  The media series contains audiovisual documentation of RWF events found throughout the collection.
  Items in this series are arranged in chronological order by format.
  - Subseries 1A: Audiocassettes - Access Copies
    Conditions Governing Access
    Audio materials have not been preserved and may not be available to researchers.
  - Subseries 1B: Audiocassettes - Originals
    - Panel Discussion: "Liability", 1 Nov 1986 (Box 3, Folder 20, Object ID: 229.0001)
      Format: Audiocassette
      TRT: Unknown
      Moderator: Judith Charles
      Panelist: Frank Picola
    - Panel Discussion: "How to Market Gourmet Food", 3 Feb 1992 (Box 3, Folder 20, Object ID: 229.0002)
      Moderator and Panelists: Unknown
    - Panel Discussion: "How to Get Effective Press Coverage", 1 Feb 1993 (Box 3, Folder 20, Object ID: 229.0003)
      Moderator: Terry Frishman
      Panelists: Julie Mautner, Irene Sax, Arthur Schwartz
    - Seminar: "How to Raise Money for Business Startup or Expansion", 1 Mar 1993 (Box 3, Folder 20, Object ID: 229.0004)
      Moderator: Rochelle Labarkis
      Panelists: Jenny Lam, Sarwar Salam, Sandra Vega, Nedege Volcy
  - Subseries 2A: Videorecording - Access Copies
    Video materials have not been preserved and may not be available to researchers.
  - Subseries 2B: Videorecording - Originals
    - RWF Pacesetters Award Winners, 23 Aug 1995 (Box 3, Folder 20, Object ID: 229.0005)
      Format: VHS
      TRT: 00:13:00